Guide to the Robert J. Havighurst Papers 1921-1991
University of Chicago Library
- Series X: Cross-Cultural and International Studies
  - Subseries 1: American Indian Education
    - Indian Higher Education (Box 126, Folder 13)
    - McKinley, Francis (Box 126, Folder 14)
    - Minnesota Publication Project (Box 126, Folder 15)
    - Nat. Co. of Churches (Box 126, Folder 16)
    - The Dilemma of the American Indian: Can Education Serve Two Contrasting Cultures? RJH, Spring 1973 (Box 126, Folder 17)
    - Applied Anthropology-Reviews (Box 126, Folder 18)
    - Public Relations-Indian Study (Box 126, Folder 19)
    - Indian Slides (Box 126, Folder 20)
    - Writing Project (Box 126, Folder 21)
    - Indian Study PR (Box 126, Folder 22)
    - Copyright Matters-Indian Study (Box 127, Folder 1)
    - Personnel (Box 127, Folder 2)
    - Progress Reports (Box 127, Folder 3)
    - Miscellaneous re: Indian Reports (Box 127, Folder 4)
    - National Study American Indian Education Patent Reports (Box 127, Folder 5)
    - NSAIE Accounts (Box 127, Folder 6)
    - Indian Budget Matters (Box 127, Folder 7)
    - Indian Study RM Fund (Box 127, Folder 8)
    - Other Finances (Box 127, Folder 9)
    - USOE-Thomas Moorefield (Box 127, Folder 10)
    - Tentative Outline of Final Report and Recommendations, Indian Study, Sept 1970 (Box 127, Folder 11)
    - Responsibility of the Federal Government for the Education of Indian Youth (Box 127, Folder 12)
    - Goals of Indian Education (Box 127, Folder 13)
    - NSAIE, Evaluation of the Present Situation (Box 127, Folder 14)
    - General Findings from Field Research, Indian Study (Box 127, Folder 15)
    - Tentative Generalizations from Field Research (Box 127, Folder 16)
    - Groups of Schools (Box 127, Folder 17)
    - General Propositions, National Study, American Indian Education (Box 127, Folder 18)
    - Report to Estelle re: Tribal Cult and Curriculum, w/Tables (Box 127, Folder 19)
    - Q’s for Others and Ray, BB (Box 127, Folder 20)
    - Boarding School Paper (Box 127, Folder 21)
    - Notes on Bdg Schools (Box 127, Folder 22)
    - Books MS Cabins (Box 128, Folder 1)
    - Classroom Stuff (Box 128, Folder 2)
    - Hoopa Stuff (Box 128, Folder 3)
    - Chapters for Indian Book (Box 128, Folder 4)
    - Indian Speech (Box 128, Folder 5)
    - Ch 1, Population (Box 128, Folder 6)
    - Whiteriver, Arizona Conference of Apache Indians for NS of AIE (Box 128, Folder 7)
    - Indian Study Proposal (Box 128, Folder 8)
    - Colorado (Box 128, Folder 9)
    - National Study of American Indian Education (Box 128, Folder 10)
    - La Pointe Series (Box 128, Folder 11)
    - Developing the Project (Box 128, Folder 12)
    - Comments on Report (Box 128, Folder 13)
    - Papers Continuing the Final Report (Box 128, Folder 14)
    - Progress Reports, 1968-1969 (Box 128, Folder 15)
    - Final Report Listing, July 1970 (Box 128, Folder 16)
    - Policy on Indian Education (Box 128, Folder 17)
    - Progress Report-April 1970, American Indian Study (Box 128, Folder 18)
    - The National Study of American Indian Education-Grouping of School Systems (Box 128, Folder 19)
    - National Study of American Indian Education (Box 128, Folder 20)
    - Kelly-RJH Interview, History of BIA (Box 128, Folder 21)
    - Research on Indian Education Publications (Box 128, Folder 22)
    - University of Chicago Press Indian Monograph (Box 129, Folder 1)
    - Readings in Anthropology, 390 (Box 129, Folder 2)
    - Sociology 390 (Box 129, Folder 3)
    - Indian Education (Box 129, Folder 4)
    - Published Indians (Box 129, Folder 5)
    - Data (Box 129, Folder 6)
    - Indian Organizations (Box 129, Folder 7)
    - Beuke-Indian Research (Box 129, Folder 8)
    - NAHO (Box 129, Folder 9)
    - Alaska Land Claims (Box 129, Folder 10)
    - 1977 Indian Match (Box 129, Folder 11)
    - Advocates for Indian Education (Box 129, Folder 12)
    - Marion Tumbleweed Beach (Box 129, Folder 13)
    - National Study of American Indian Education Research Reports, v.1-3 (Box 129, Folder 14)
    - The Status of American Indian Education, by Herbert A. Aurbach and Estelle Fuchs (Box 130, Folder 1)
    - Proposals (Box 130, Folder 2)
    - Report (Box 130, Folder 3)
    - San Francisco State (Box 130, Folder 4)
    - Collier, John Jr. (Box 130, Folder 5)
    - Myers Chico Hoopa (Box 130, Folder 6)
    - University of Minnesota (Box 130, Folder 7)
    - North Carolina State University (Box 130, Folder 8)
    - Oklahoma State University (Box 130, Folder 9)
    - National Study of American Indian Education, Correspondence, General, A-H (Box 130, Folder 10)
    - National Study of American Indian Education, Correspondence, General, I-Q (Box 131, Folder 1)
    - National Study of American Indian Education, Correspondence, General, R-Z (Box 131, Folder 2)
    - Indian Education Annals (Box 131, Folder 3)
    - The Extent and Significance of Suicide Among American Indians Today (Box 131, Folder 4)
    - Copyright Matters (Box 131, Folder 5)
    - Mission Schools (Box 131, Folder 6)
    - PTA Indians (Box 131, Folder 7)
    - Publications on Indian Society (Box 131, Folder 8)
    - Reviews-To Him on This Earth (Box 131, Folder 9)
    - Boarding Schools (Box 131, Folder 10)
    - Chapter 1-Design of the Study (Box 131, Folder 11)
    - Navajo Health (Box 131, Folder 12)
    - Chapter I: Design of the Study (Box 131, Folder 13)
    - Curriculum (Box 131, Folder 14)
    - American Indian Education, Study of Personnel (Box 131, Folder 15)
    - Teacher Questionnaire, Anonymous (Box 131, Folder 16)
    - Teacher Data (Box 132, Folder 1)
    - Teachers and Pupils (Box 132, Folder 2)
    - Am. Ind. Teachers (Box 132, Folder 3)
    - Chicago, O-WAI-YA-WA (Box 132, Folder 4)
    - Map Showing Location of Indians in Chicago (Box 132, Folder 5)
    - Chi Indians MS (Box 132, Folder 6)
    - American Indian Center-Research Data (Box 132, Folder 7)
    - Urban Indians (1 of 2) (Box 132, Folder 8)
    - Urban Indians (2 of 2) (Box 132, Folder 9)
    - Los Angeles Indians (Box 132, Folder 10)
    - Minneapolis Urban Indians (Box 132, Folder 11)
    - Phillips School (Box 132, Folder 12)
    - Community Background Descriptions-Robeson County (Box 132, Folder 13)
    - Bibliography on Indian Ed (Box 133, Folder 1)
    - Community Background Description-Lumbee Indians in Baltimore (Box 133, Folder 2)
    - Film Evaluation of Eskimo Education, by John Collier (Box 133, Folder 3)
    - San Carlos Apache Indian Res. And Bylas, AZ; Fort Thomas Public Schools (Box 133, Folder 4)
    - The Rosebud Sioux Reservation (Box 133, Folder 5)
    - Final Reports: Community Background (Box 133, Folder 6)
    - Neah Bay: The Makah (Box 133, Folder 7)
    - Community Background Reports: Taholah, Quinault Reservation (Box 133, Folder 8)
    - Community Background Report: Bethel, Alaska (Box 133, Folder 9)
    - Laguna Indian Reservation and Acoma Indian Reservation (Box 133, Folder 10)
    - Pima Central and Blackwater Schools, Arizona (Box 133, Folder 11)
    - Papago Reservation, Sellis, Arizona (Box 133, Folder 12)
    - Angoon, Alaska (Box 133, Folder 13)
    - Teachers for American Indian Youth, Series IV, n. 5 (Box 133, Folder 14)
    - Arizona Technical Report-National Study, Amer. Ind. Ed. (Box 133, Folder 15)
    - 1975-Hannon’s Appointment (Box 133, Folder 16)
    - Aurbach (Box 133, Folder 17)
    - Community Background Reports-Second Mesa Day School (Box 133, Folder 18)
    - Community Background Studies-Baltimore (Box 133, Folder 19)
    - NSAIE Final Financial Report Material (1 of 2) (Box 134, Folder 1)
    - NSAIE Final Financial Report Material (2 of 2) (Box 134, Folder 2)
    - Office of Education and BIH Compliance (Box 134, Folder 3)
    - Indian Study Commission (Box 134, Folder 4)
    - Self Studies (Box 134, Folder 5)
    - Quinlan Self Study (Box 134, Folder 6)
    - Colorado (Box 134, Folder 7)
    - Research on Indian Ed. (Box 135, Folder 1)
    - Rough Rock (Box 135, Folder 2)
    - White River Education Conference (Box 135, Folder 3)
    - Bruce Birchard (Box 135, Folder 4)
    - Risemberg, Adriana (Box 135, Folder 5)
    - George Scott (Box 135, Folder 6)
    - Stanley (Box 135, Folder 7)
    - Ward, Rose Marie (Box 135, Folder 8)
    - John White (Box 135, Folder 9)
    - To Be Done (Box 135, Folder 10)
    - Indian Study Field Directory (Box 135, Folder 11)
    - Reports by Field Directors on Sampling Procedures, Tucson, 2/22/69 (Box 135, Folder 12)
    - Student Interview (Box 135, Folder 13)
    - Chicago Teacher Interview (Box 135, Folder 14)
    - Past Interviews (Box 135, Folder 15)
    - School Administration (Box 135, Folder 16)
    - Influential Person Chapter (Box 135, Folder 17)
    - Influential People Interview (Box 135, Folder 18)
    - Interviews Material (Box 136, Folder 1)
    - Research Notes (Box 136, Folder 2)
    - Basic Working Papers on Interviews (Box 136, Folder 3)
    - Cross-Center Teacher Reliability Master Sheet and Score Sheet (Box 136, Folder 4)
    - Indian Field Work Papers (Box 136, Folder 5)
    - Birch Working Papers (Box 136, Folder 6)
    - Concordence Study (Box 136, Folder 7)
    - Cross-Center Student Reliability Master Sheet and Score Sheets (Box 136, Folder 8)
    - Cross-Center Influential Person Reliability Master Sheets and Score Sheets (Box 136, Folder 9)
    - Reliability of Ratings (Box 136, Folder 10)
    - Notes (Box 136, Folder 11)
    - Reliability Studies (Box 136, Folder 12)
    - Reliability of Comparisons of Rating Scales for Different Regional Centers (Box 136, Folder 13)
    - Indian-SD (Box 136, Folder 14)
    - Semantics Results (Box 137, Folder 1)
    - Dryer Paper on Sem. Dil. (Box 137, Folder 2)
    - Parent: Distribution of Ratings Opinion of the School (Box 137, Folder 3)
    - II Attitudes and Opinions: Retribal Culture and Language (Box 137, Folder 4)
    - Communication and Understanding (Box 137, Folder 5)
    - IV-S and P Opinion of Teacher’s Attitudes toward S’s and P’s (Box 137, Folder 6)
    - Indian Attitudes Toward Formal Ed (Box 137, Folder 7)
    - Colorado (Box 137, Folder 8)
    - Parental Involvement in School (Box 137, Folder 9)
    - Memos re: P,T,S Concordances (Box 137, Folder 10)
    - Memos on Use of Scales (Box 137, Folder 11)
    - Outline of Paper on Int. Data (Box 137, Folder 12)
    - Memos re Concordances (Box 137, Folder 13)
    - Info from BA on Control, Curr. Plan (Box 137, Folder 14)
    - RJH Memos and Reports (Box 137, Folder 15)
    - Parent Scale Results and Comments (Box 137, Folder 16)
    - Student Scale Results (Box 137, Folder 17)
    - Teacher Scale Results (Box 137, Folder 18)
    - Teacher Query (Box 137, Folder 19)
    - Bibliographers (Box 137, Folder 20)
    - Tucson Conference Memo (Box 137, Folder 21)
    - Memos for Sept. Wash. Conference (Box 137, Folder 22)
    - Arizona Reports (Box 137, Folder 23)
    - Chicago Reports (Box 137, Folder 24)
    - Colorado Reports (Box 137, Folder 25)
    - North Carolina Reports (Box 137, Folder 26)
    - San Francisco Reports (Box 137, Folder 27)
    - Bibliography of Indian ed. Reading (Box 137, Folder 28)
    - Urban Indian Stuff (Box 137, Folder 29)
    - Analysis of San Fran. Student Scales (Box 137, Folder 30)
    - Report on Denver Conference on Indian Education-Gen. Scott (Box 137, Folder 31)
    - Memo-Coding of Student Interviews, 10/14/68 (Box 138, Folder 1)
    - Parent Interview Rating Sheet (Box 138, Folder 2)
    - The Use of the Flanders Interaction Analysis (Box 138, Folder 3)
    - Classroom Atmosphere Ratings, 10/17/68 (Box 138, Folder 4)
    - Classroom Atmosphere (Box 138, Folder 5)
    - Form for Personnel-National Study, American Indian Education, Nov. 69 (Box 138, Folder 6)
    - Student Interview Rating Scales, 1/14/69 (Box 138, Folder 7)
    - Student Interview Rating Scales Analysis (Box 138, Folder 8)
    - Student Interview Schedule (Box 138, Folder 9)
    - Procedure for Establishing Reliability, June 13, 1969 (Box 138, Folder 10)
    - Studying the Reliability of Our Rating Scales (Box 138, Folder 11)
    - 1969 Memo (Box 138, Folder 12)
    - Memo 15-6-69 Procedure for Establishing Reliability of Student, Interview Rating Scales (Box 138, Folder 13)
    - Instrument for the Sociometric Study of the School (Box 138, Folder 14)
    - Parent Interview Rating Scales, June 11, Final Version (with memo) (Box 138, Folder 15)
    - Memo: Student Interview Rating Sheets (Box 138, Folder 16)
    - Student Interview Rating Scales and "Rating Sheets" (Box 138, Folder 17)
    - Parent Interview Rating Scales (Box 138, Folder 18)
    - Student Interview Ok’d (Box 138, Folder 19)
    - Classroom Atmosphere Ratings, May 23, 1969 (Box 138, Folder 20)
    - Discussion of Experience on Student Interview Ratings (Box 138, Folder 21)
    - Memo re: Rating Scale for Influential Person Interviews (Box 138, Folder 22)
    - Field Length Directory (Box 138, Folder 23)
    - Guide for Dormitory Observations (Collier) (Box 138, Folder 24)
    - Memo on Influential Persons-Ratings 10/27/69 (Box 138, Folder 25)
    - Analysis of Interview and Questionnaire Data (Box 138, Folder 26)
    - Visual Observational Schedule for Community and School Culture (Box 138, Folder 27)
    - U. of Colorado Team Progress Report, Colorado (Box 138, Folder 28)
    - A Tentative Approach to the School Setting, Michener (Box 138, Folder 29)
    - Untitled: Outline for Organizing Data for Final Analysis and Report (Box 138, Folder 30)
    - Working Paper Ratings from Interviews, CN, RJH (Box 138, Folder 31)
    - The Chicago Indian Community (Box 138, Folder 32)
    - Indian Students in Chicago Schools (Box 138, Folder 33)
    - The American Indian in Chicago: The Hidden People (Box 138, Folder 34)
    - Parent-Face Sheet, Chicago Form (Box 138, Folder 35)
    - Information from Chicago School Teachers (Box 138, Folder 36)
    - American Indian Study-Miscellaneous Ratings (Box 138, Folder 37)
    - Draw-a-Man Test (Box 138, Folder 38)
    - Student A (Box 138, Folder 39)
    - Classroom Atmosphere Rating Scales (Box 138, Folder 40)
    - The Performance of Indian Children in the Draw-a-Man Test (Box 139, Folder 1)
    - Short Interview Item Totals (Box 139, Folder 1)
    - Trial Research-The Performance of American Indian Children in the Draw-a-Man Test (Box 139, Folder 3)
    - Indian Draw-a-Man (Box 139, Folder 4)
    - Table 2: Average IQ Scores Earned by Indian Children on the Draw-a-Man Test (Box 139, Folder 5)
    - ETS: Indian Study Instruments (Box 139, Folder 6)
    - Instruments I (Box 139, Folder 7)
    - Influential Persons Interview Schedule Chicago Form #2 (Box 139, Folder 8)
    - Observations of and Information on Individual Indian Pupils in Chicago Schools (Box 139, Folder 9)
    - Teacher Questionnaire, Part B (Box 139, Folder 10)
    - Student C and B (Box 139, Folder 11)
    - Teacher Interview Schedule, Chicago Form (Box 139, Folder 12)
    - Influential Persons Interview Schedule (Box 139, Folder 13)
    - Teacher Group Discussion (Box 139, Folder 14)
    - Letters to Teacher Requesting them to Rate Students (Box 139, Folder 15)
    - Diary-Social Life Space (Teacher) (Box 139, Folder 16)
    - Composition Rating Scales (Box 139, Folder 17)
  - Subseries 2: Anglo Versus Native Cultures
    - Anglos vs. Native Cultures (Box 139, Folder 18)
    - Anglos vs. Native Cultures, copy 1 (Box 139, Folder 19)
    - Anglos vs. Native Cultures, copy 2, vols 3 and 4 (Box 140, Folder 1)
    - Anglos vs. Native Cultures, copy 2, part 1 (Box 140, Folder 2)
    - Anglos vs. Native Cultures, copy 2, part 2 (Box 140, Folder 3)
    - Land Party-Reserve (Box 141, Folder 1)
    - A VI Changes (Box 141, Folder 2)
    - CIX AS Policy Res. (Box 141, Folder 3)
    - Reservation Chapters 5-7 (Box 141, Folder 4)
    - Australia (Box 141, Folder 5)
    - ABO Math Ability (Box 141, Folder 6)
    - Australia Project (Box 141, Folder 7)
    - FCAATSI (Box 141, Folder 8)
    - Vanben Reports, Preschool (Box 141, Folder 9)
    - AVIII Cult Pluralism (Box 141, Folder 10)
    - Race Relations (Box 141, Folder 11)
    - Ch. 12 Women, 1973 (Box 141, Folder 12)
    - Maori Education (Box 141, Folder 13)
    - CVIII Labor Force (Box 141, Folder 14)
    - Terrain Cult. (Box 141, Folder 15)
    - Cassette Tapes: Mr. Hall-Aboriginal WEIPA Radio Address (Box 141, Folder 16)
    - Brag’s Material (Box 141, Folder 17)
    - New Zealand-Bibliography (Box 141, Folder 18)
    - NZ-Reservation (Box 141, Folder 19)
    - NZ-Census (Box 141, Folder 20)
    - NZ Ch 2-VII (Box 142, Folder 1)
    - New Zealand Council for Educational Research (Box 142, Folder 2)
    - 9. Education (Box 142, Folder 3)
    - Australian Education (Box 142, Folder 4)
    - Indians (Box 142, Folder 5)
    - Women’s Roles Res (Box 142, Folder 6)
    - Future of Education (Box 142, Folder 7)
    - Labor Force Reserve (Box 142, Folder 8)
    - Race Relations (Box 142, Folder 9)
    - Education-Indian (Box 142, Folder 10)
    - Indian Biblio Reserve (Box 142, Folder 11)
    - Indian Revision (Box 142, Folder 12)
    - British and Indians (Box 142, Folder 13)
    - Reservation Settlements (Box 142, Folder 14)
    - Indian Reserve (Box 142, Folder 15)
    - Nature Society (Box 142, Folder 16)
    - Indian War (Box 142, Folder 17)
    - Cherokee Reserve (Box 142, Folder 18)
    - IV Withdrawal (Box 142, Folder 19)
    - McLeod (Box 142, Folder 20)
    - Am. Indian Policy Commission (Box 142, Folder 21)
    - Intro and Chapter 1, Reserve (Box 142, Folder 22)
    - Ch 5, Maps (Box 142, Folder 23)
    - Maps and Tables, N3 (Box 142, Folder 24)
    - Ans T (Box 143, Folder 1)
    - Indian Politics (Box 143, Folder 2)
    - Race Relations and Women’s Roles (Box 143, Folder 3)
    - USA (Box 143, Folder 4)
    - NZ Extra (Box 143, Folder 5)
    - Aust. Reserve (Box 143, Folder 6)
    - Land Policy (Box 143, Folder 7)
    - XI Policy (Box 143, Folder 8)
  - Subseries 3: Latin America Studies
    - Dr. Gonzalo Aguierre Beltran (Box 143, Folder 9)
    - Comparing Latin American and No. American Higher Education (Box 143, Folder 10)
    - Higher Education Paper (Box 143, Folder 11)
    - Latin American Speech (Box 143, Folder 12)
    - Higher Ed in Latin America (Box 144, Folder 1)
    - Education 404A: Society and Education in Latin America Reading List (Box 144, Folder 2)
    - RJH Pass on LA and NA Higher Ed (Box 144, Folder 3)
    - Latin America (Box 144, Folder 4)
    - Argentina-Amerindians (Box 144, Folder 5)
    - Texas A M (Box 144, Folder 6)
    - Achieving Adult Social and Economic Status (Box 144, Folder 7)
    - Children’s World in Relation to School Programs (Box 144, Folder 8)
    - Ed. 411-Development of Concepts (Box 144, Folder 9)
    - Firm Foundation (Box 144, Folder 10)
    - 404A: Society and Education in Latin America (Box 144, Folder 11)
    - Argentina (Box 144, Folder 12)
    - Americana Latin America (Box 144, Folder 13)
    - Chile (Box 144, Folder 14)
    - Economic Development (Box 144, Folder 15)
    - Community and School (Box 144, Folder 16)
    - State and School (Box 145, Folder 1)
    - Tables on Brazil (Box 145, Folder 2)
    - Generalities-Brazilian Research (Box 145, Folder 3)
    - Pastore, Jose (Box 145, Folder 4)
    - Occupational Prestige (Box 145, Folder 5)
    - Data Library-Berkeley (Box 145, Folder 6)
    - Rahl (Box 145, Folder 7)
    - Pernambuco (Box 145, Folder 8)
    - R. Grande de Sul (Box 145, Folder 9)
    - UNESCO Before 1960 (Box 145, Folder 10)
    - Latin American Ditto Masters (Box 145, Folder 11)
    - Seminar on Higher Education in the Americas (Box 145, Folder 12)
    - Materials for the Seminar on Higher Education in the Americas (Box 145, Folder 13)
    - Ed and Soc. In Latin America (Box 146, Folder 1)
    - Series on Latin America (Box 146, Folder 2)
    - Society and Education in Latin America (Box 146, Folder 3)
    - La Educacion 18 Aberil-Junio 1960 (Box 146, Folder 4)
    - Ch XIII (Box 146, Folder 5)
    - Society and Education in Brazil (2 copies) (Box 146, Folder 6)
    - Psychology 350-A,B,C (Box 146, Folder 7)
    - Humanities Council (Box 146, Folder 8)
    - Brazil Correspondence (Box 147, Folder 1)
    - America-Brazil (Box 147, Folder 2)
    - Brazil Write-Up (Box 147, Folder 3)
  - Subseries 4: Coping Styles and Achievement
    - Coping Styles and Achievement: A Cross-National Study of School Children, v. I, manuscripts, proposals, 1981 (Box 147, Folder 4)
    - Coping Styles and Achievement: A Cross-National Study of School Children, v. 2, manuscripts, proposals, 1981 (Box 148, Folder 1)
    - Coping Styles and Achievement: A Cross-National Study of School Children, v. 3, manuscripts, proposals, 1981 (Box 148, Folder 2)
    - Coping Styles and Achievement: A Cross-National Study of School Children, v. 4, manuscripts, proposals, 1981 (Box 148, Folder 3)
    - Coping Styles and Achievement: A Cross-National Study of School Children, v. 5, manuscripts, proposals, 1981 (Box 149, Folder 1)
    - Coping Styles and Achievement: An International Study, 1979 (1 of 2) (Box 149, Folder 2)
    - Coping Styles and Achievement: An International Study, 1979 (2 of 2) (Box 149, Folder 3)
    - Manaster-Havighurst book, raw material, 1968-1970 (Box 150, Folder 1)
    - Coping Styles and Achievement: A Cross-National Study of School Children, v. 5, manuscripts, proposals, 1981 (Box 150, Folder 2)
    - Correspondence-Texas Cross Nat’l (Box 150, Folder 3)
    - X-Nat’l-Quarterly Progress Reports (Box 151, Folder 1)
    - Suggested Plan for Describing and Interpreting the Findings from the Stage I Analyses-Texas Cross-Nat’l (Box 151, Folder 2)
    - Cross-National Project-University of Texas-Proposal and Instruments (Box 151, Folder 3)
    - Memoranda-General (Box 151, Folder 4)
    - Peck, Aug 1979, with report on 14-year-olds (Box 151, Folder 5)
    - Peck-1975-78 (Box 151, Folder 6)
    - Peck-APA-1977 (Box 151, Folder 7)
    - K. Miller (Box 151, Folder 8)
    - X-National Project (Box 151, Folder 9)
    - Cross National Budget (Box 151, Folder 10)
    - Budget-Texas Cross National (Box 151, Folder 11)
    - SocioCultural Premises (Box 151, Folder 12)
    - Cross National Study-1964 (Box 151, Folder 13)
    - Editorial Committee Meeting (Box 151, Folder 14)
    - Personality and Culture (Box 152, Folder 1)
    - National Character (Box 152, Folder 2)
    - England Write-Up (Box 152, Folder 3)
    - Vol. I Material (Box 152, Folder 4)
    - Yugoslavia-RW (Box 152, Folder 5)
    - National Directory of Latin Americanists (Box 152, Folder 6)
    - Chile Biblio. (Box 152, Folder 7)
    - Japan-Analysis of Variance (Box 152, Folder 8)
    - Chicago Write-Up (Box 152, Folder 9)
    - Mexico Data, Summer 1970 (Box 152, Folder 10)
    - Mexico-Recent, 1972 (Box 152, Folder 11)
    - Cultural Motivation (Box 152, Folder 12)
    - Education-Social Mobility in Four Societies (Box 152, Folder 13)
    - Miscellaneous (Box 152, Folder 14)
    - Canada (Box 152, Folder 15)
    - Russia (Box 152, Folder 16)
    - Copy Study Material (Box 152, Folder 17)
    - Instruments (Box 153, Folder 1)
    - Miscellaneous Instruments (Box 153, Folder 2)
    - BRS-Occ (Box 153, Folder 3)
    - Texas Cross-National Study (Box 153, Folder 4)
    - Stage III-Sentence Completion (Box 153, Folder 5)
    - Views of Lite (Box 153, Folder 6)
    - Instruments (Box 153, Folder 7)
    - Current, Texas (Box 153, Folder 8)
    - Problems of Method and Instruments in Cross-National Research (Box 153, Folder 9)
    - Instruments, Miscellaneous (Box 153, Folder 10)
    - A Critical Study of the Literature on Cross-National Studies with Psychological Instruments (Box 153, Folder 11)
- Series XI: Seneca Research Project
  - Interviews, notes, budget and expenses, 1930-1951, 1979-1980 (Box 153, Folder 12)
- Series XII: Adulthood, Aging, and the Life Cycle
  - Subseries 1: Human development and the Life Span
    - NSSE Choice of Subjects (Box 154, Folder 1)